Boldly going where no blonde has gone.
Legally Blonde is a comedy, romance film directed by Robert Luketic.
Fashionable sorority queen Elle Woods has it all, but,
she wants nothing more than to be Mrs.
Warner Huntington III.
But he dumps her before heading to Harvard Law School.
Elle rallies all of her resources and gets into
Harvard, determined to win him back.
While there, she figures out that there is more to herself than just good looks.
Elle Woods, played by Reese Witherspoon.
Emmetten Richmond, played by Luke Wilson.
Vivian Kensington, played by Selma Blair.
Warner Huntington III, played by Matthew Davis.
Professor Callahan, played by Victor Garber.
Paulette, played by Jennifer Coolidge.
Legally Blonde is a 2001 American comedy film directed by Robert Luketic
and written by Karen McCullah Lutz and Kirsten Smith.
Based on Amanda Brown's novel, it stars Reese Witherspoon, Luke Wilson, Selma
Blair, Matthew Davis, Victor Garber, and Jennifer Coolidge.
The story follows Elle Woods (Witherspoon), a sorority girl who attempts to win back her ex-boyfriend Warner Huntington III (Davis) by getting a Juris
Doctor degree at Harvard Law School, and in the process, overcomes stereotypes against blondes and triumphs as a successful lawyer.
The outline of Legally Blonde originated from Brown's experiences as a blonde going to Stanford Law School while being obsessed
with fashion and beauty, reading Elle  magazine, and frequently clashing with the personalities of her peers.
In 2000, Brown met producer Marc Platt, who helped her
develop her manuscript into a novel.
Platt brought in screenwriters McCullah Lutz and Smith
to adapt the book into a motion picture.
The project caught the attention of Luketic, an
Australian director new to Hollywood.
The film was released on July 13, 2001, and was a hit with audiences, grossing $142 million worldwide on an $18 million budget,
as well as receiving positive reviews from critics, with praise for Witherspoon's performance in particular.
It was nominated for a Golden Globe Award for Best
Motion Picture: Musical or Comedy.
Witherspoon received a Golden Globe nomination for Best Actress – Motion Picture
Musical or Comedy, and the 2002 MTV Movie Award for Best Female Performance.
A sequel, Legally Blonde 2: Red, White & Blonde, was released in 2003, while
another sequel was announced to be in development in 2018.
Legally Blonde also spawned a media franchise with various adaptations, including a stage musical, which premiered on Broadway in 2007, a direct-to-video spin-off, Legally
Blondes, released in 2009, and an upcoming prequel television series about Woods's high school years, Elle, scheduled to premiere in 2026 on Amazon Prime Video.
The film explores themes of father murder, blonde,
superficiality, beauty salon, law school.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.